Richard Hendriks

Programmer

Richard hails from Tulsa. He has earned degrees from the University of Oklahoma and Stanford. (Go Sooners and Cardinal!) Before starting Pied Piper, he worked for Hooli as a part time software developer. While his work focuses on applied information theory, mostly optimizing lossless compression schema of both the length-limited and adaptive variants, his non-work interests range widely, everything from quantum computing to chaos theory. He could tell you about it, but THAT would NOT be a "length-limited" conversation!

Twitter:

SoundCloud: https://soundcloud.example.com/dandymusicnl

Work Experience

CEO/President

Pied Piper

2013-12-01 - 2014-12-01

Pied Piper is a multi-platform technology based on a proprietary universal compression algorithm that has consistently fielded high Weisman Scores™ that are not merely competitive, but approach the theoretical limit of lossless compression.

- Build an algorithm for artist to detect if their music was violating copy right infringement laws
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

Volunteer Experience

Teacher

CoderDojo

2012-01-01 - 2013-01-01

Global movement of free coding clubs for young people.

Education

• Bachelor: Information Technology

University of Oklahoma 2011-06-01 - 2014-01-01

Awards

• Digital Compression Pioneer Award

Techcrunch

2014-11-01

There is no spoon.

Publications

Video compression for 3d media

Hooli

2014-10-01

Innovative middle-out compression algorithm that changes the way we store data.

Skills

Web Development

Master

HTML, CSS, Javascript

Compression

Master

Mpeg, MP4, GIF

Languages

English

Native speaker

Interests

Wildlife

Ferrets, Unicorns

References

• Erlich Bachman

It is my pleasure to recommend Richard, his performance working as a consultant for Main St. Company proved that he will be a valuable addition to any company.

Projects

Miss Direction

2016-08-24 - 2016-08-24

A mapping engine that misguides you

Won award at AlHacks 2016, Built by all women team of newbie programmers, Using modern technologies such as GoogleMaps, Chrome Extension and Javascript

missdirection.example.com